Nalini Mahajan

Front End Developer

Have a keen interest in technology and a hunger for learning new things. Have done the Full Stack Web Development Program of Newton School and want to move further in **Front-End Development**. Have nearly 3 years of experience in the Travel Industry which has given lots of insights into customer relations, management and working under pressurized situations and set time limits.

RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS

Newton School Coding Boot Camp, Newton School

January 2022 - September 2022

- Learning Full Stack Web Development MERN Stack.
- Problem solving with DSA
- Worked on various projects: Food Order App, Todo App, 2 player Ping-Pong game and responsive websites.

Front End Development Libraries, freeCodeCamp

August 2022 - September 2022

- Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework.
- Libraries covered: Bootstrap, jQuery, SASS, React, Redux.
- Submitted projects: Random Quote Machine, Markdown Previewer, Drum Machine, JavaScript Calculator and Pomodoro Clock.

Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp

June 2022 - September 2022

- Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework.
- Tech Stacks covered: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Submitted projects: Survey Form, Tribute Page, Technical Documentation Page, Product Landing Page and Personal Portfolio Webpage.

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, freeCodeCamp

June 2022 - July 2022

- Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework.
- Core concepts of JavaScript.
- Problem solving with JavaScript.



Pune, MH 412307



+91 9806370793



☑ nilumahajan793@gmail.comIinkedin.com/in/nalinimahajan



codepen.io/nalini793

SKILLS

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

React.js

TypeScript

Node.js

Express.js

MongoDB

Rest APIs

Core Java

SpringBoot

MySQL

PROJECTS

Todo App 🕜

HTML, CSS, React.js, TypeScript A responsive Todo List App,

integrating CRUD operations with beautiful UI.

Food Order App 🕜

HTML, CSS, React.js

A responsive food order web app to order meals with Cart overlay and complete integration of state management.

2 Player Ping-Pong 🕜

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

A classic 2 player game recreated with sound effects; paddles are controlled by keyboard.

& Many more projects



WORK EXPERIENCE

Rainbow Trade Fair Tours Pvt. Ltd., Jaipur (RJ) Operation Executive

June 2017 - March 2020

- Developing products and managing operations for Trade fair travel for groups as well as FITs.
- Inventory Management: Keeping the track of contracts, payments & execution time limits with suppliers.
- Been on site as a Tour Leader for Medica 2018 at Dusseldorf, Germany for a delegation of 150+ pax.
- Making and managing bookings using key comparison points, through online portals such as Rezlive, TBO, Expedia (TAAP), Bulktrip, etc.

INTERNSHIPS

Air India, Indore

April 2016 - June 2016

- Part of MBA Curriculum.
- Handled customer service issues, including unhappy clients, missed flights, mistakes in the itinerary, and other last-minute problems.

CA K.D. Saraf, Indore

December 2013 - December 2014

- Joined as Article Assistant, got first-hand experience in Audit, Taxation & Accounting.
- Received various trainings from ICAI.
- Cleared various stages of Charted Accountancy course:
 - o December 2011: Cleared CA-CPT
 - June 2013: Cleared CA-IPCC (1st group)

EDUCATION

2017	Masters of Business Administration (Tourism) International Institute of Professional Studies, Indore	7.45/10
2015	Bachelor of Commerce Annie Besant College, Indore	58.42%
2011	Intermediate (Class XII) Govt. Devi Ahilya HS Excellence School No.1, Khargone	76.2%
2009	Matriculation (Class X) Saraswati Vidya Mandir HS School, Khargone	80%

SKILLS

- Team Player
- Critical Thinking
- Communication Skills
- Quick Learner
- Creative Abilities
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability & flexibility

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Love solving puzzles
- Writing poetry
- Reading books
- Learning new things, recently learned Morse Code to understand accessibility.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date: 07th November 2022 Location: Pune Nalini Mahajan